

Octavery Kamil

Cellphone. 62-812 8320 8765 Email: verykamil@gmail.com Skype: verykamil2014

Address: Pamulang Permai I, Blok A33/ No. 8 Tangerang Selatan 15417 Banten - Indonesia

Summary of Professional Experience

Currently Mr. Kamil is an associate researcher at at AIDS Research Center Atma Jaya University, Jakarta Indonesia. He was the research team leaders for some studies and involved as a team member in some others. His passion is empowerment and civil society participation on AIDS programming.

Mr. Kamil has just finished his study and received Doctorate degree from Doctoral Program at Department of Sociology, University of Indonesia, Jakarta. He received a scholarship from AIDS International Training and Research Program (AITRP) from University of Illinois at Chicago and became an AITRP fellow since Fall 2011. His research topic is Social Capital among injecting drug users. He is active in AIDS Coalition for Drugs Policy Change in Jakarta.

Mr. Kamil was a Chief of Unit for Injecting Drug User Intervention at ASA Program - Family Health International Indonesia. He involved and led the development of intervention program for HIV prevention on Injecting Drug Users at 8 provinces in Indonesia. He provided training and technical assistance for local NGOs staff and government officials on HIV prevention program for injecting drug users.

He started his career on health reproductive for youth then moved to AIDS field and had intensive experience as NGO activist since 1991. On year 1997, he moved to United States for 3 years and has opportunity extended his experienced on democracy issue when he involved on election monitoring. He received a research travel fellowship from Fogarty AIDS International Training and Research Program to meet researchers at University Illinois of Chicago and to attend College Problem on Drugs Dependence (CPDD) 66th Annual Scientific Meeting in San Juan, Puerto Rico on 2004.

On year 2008 he joined Atmajaya Catholic University – Jakarta, to start an AIDS Research Center. He wanted to develop his career on research area to give more impact on HIV/AIDS issues that he had been involved since 1993.

EDUCATION

Graduate Program: University of Indonesia, Doctoral Program, Department of Sociology, Faculty of Social Sciences and Politics, 2011-2017. Dissertation: Social Capital and Quality of Life: Mixed method study on Injecting Drug Users in Jakarta

Graduate Program: University of Indonesia, Magister Program on Management of Social Development, Department of Sociology, Faculty of Social Sciences and Politics, 2001-2004.

Thesis: Injecting Drug User Intervention: Case Study of HIV AIDS program in Jakarta.

Undergraduate Program: University of Gadjah Mada, Faculty of Psychology, Yogyakarta, Indonesia 1987 – 1996.

Thesis: Mini seminar as facilitator on Knowledge, Attitude to People with AIDS: an Experimental Study among High School students in Yogyakarta.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Center for Health Policy and Management, Faculty of Medicine, University of Gadjah Mada, Yogyakarta. 2014

Consultant. 2014.

- Developing CSS module for researchers training
- AIDS Policy Training for researchers, CSS course.

AIDS Research Center, Atma Jaya Catholic University, Jakarta, 2008 - present

Project advisor, December 2011 - June 2012

- Training of trainers on Harm Reduction
- Training and Mentoring for NGOs partners of SUM Program

Researcher, 2008 - present

National Coordinator, 2008 - 2011

• A collaboration research project between Atma Jaya University and University of Illinois at Chicago.

HIV Cooperation Program for Indonesia (HCPI), Jakarta, 2011

Consultant for National AIDS Commission (NAC), Research Working Group

 Provided technical assistance and mentoring for AIDS researchers which received research grant from HCPI through NAC

Management Sciences for Health, Inc. / Global Management Solution (GMS), Jakarta 2010 - 2011

Consultant for GMS on Dashboard Utilization for CCM GF Indonesia

• carry out oversight of Global Fund grants and principal recipients (PRs), identify problems and assist PRs to carry out solutions when needed

ASA Program- Family Health International, 2001 - 2009

Consultant for IDU Intervention Unit, 2008 - 2009

• provided technical assistance on activities related to IDU intervention as needed (project assessment, training design, data intervention analysis, facilitation, as resource person, etc.)

Chief of IDU Intervention Unit, 2005 - 2008

- managed contracts and activities related to HIV/AIDS interventions targeting IDU in Indonesia (research, situational assessments, strategic planning, proposal development, training design, technical assistance, and monitoring/evaluation)
- built network with international, national and local agencies on matters related to drugs and HIV/AIDS
- built cooperative relations with government authorities to facilitate technology transfer and the scaling-up of intervention programs to cover every province in Indonesia
- provided training, facilitation, and as resource person to NGO and government institution related to IDU Intervention

Behavior Change Specialist for Harm Reduction, 2002-2005

- monitored project on IDU intervention
- provided technical assistance and support to implementing agencies
- provided training and capacity building related activities as needed to implementing agencies and other institutions

Lentera HIV/AIDS prevention project, Indonesia Planned Parenthood Association Yogyakarta, 1993–1997

Project Manager, 1995–1997 Outreach worker, 1993 - 1996

AIDS Media and Training Center for Journalists, 1994-1996

Program Advisor, 1994–1996

• developed and led national AIDS training program for journalists in Indonesia in collaboration with LP3Y

Private Agencies Collaborating Together (PACT), 1996

Consultant, Sexual Health Training for the RESCUE AIDS project

• developed and lead sexual health training program for NGOs which reached street kids in Jakarta

Sahabat Remaja, Youth counseling service, Indonesia Planned Parenthood Association Yogyakarta, 1991–1994

Youth Counselor, 1991–1994

- provided counseling for adolescents issues
- lead reproductive health and sexuality education workshops for youth

RESEARCH

Facilitator for Civil Society Group Discussion

Identifying obstacles and enablers to increase financial and political support for Community System Strengthening, International HIV AIDS Alliance. 2014

Assessment team member/facilitator

Concept Note on Community System Strengthening: Input to EC Indonesia Country Strategic Plan 2013 – 2020, European Union's Asia Program for Indonesia, 2014

Researcher/ Analyst.

Behavioral Survey on Youth in DKI Jakarta, a Adolescents behavioral survey conducted by Provincial AIDS Commission DKI Jakarta. December 2013.

Researcher/Team leader

Analysis of HIV-sensitive Social Protection Scheme in Indonesia, A

collaboration between ARC Atma Jaya and International Labour Organization (ILO), Indonesia country office, funded by ILO Indonesia Country Office, 2011.

Researcher/ Team leader

Health Seeking Behavior among Injecting Drug Users in Bekasi, A qualitative study collaboration between ARC Atma Jaya and Burnet Institute, funded by Levy Strauss Foundation, 2009-2010.

Researcher

Sexual Network and Drugs Use Survey among Injecting Drug Users in 6

Provinces, a collaboration between ARC Atma Jaya and ASA Program/FHI, funded by Global Fund Round 4 through Family Health International, 2009-2010.

Research Team Member

Education Sector Response to HIV/AIDS, Drugs, and Sexuality in Indonesia, a collaboration study between ARC Atma Jaya and Unesco, Indonesia, funded by Unesco, 2009 – 2010.

Research Coordinator

Psychosocial Factors supporting ARV Adherence among IDU, Collaboration between Atma Jaya University and University of Illinois of Chicago, funded by NICH, USA, 2008.

Interviewer

The Sexual Network Qualitative Study on Injecting Drug Users in Indonesia and Bangladesh. Funded by FHI Asia Pacific Division, October 2004

PUBLICATION & PRESENTATION

- Outreach efforts successes and challenges in Indonesia, Regional Workshop on HIV and Drug Use "HIV Prevention, Care and Treatment for People Who Inject Drugs: A Review of evidence-based findings and best practices" Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, 2011 (oral presentation)
- **Analysis of HIV-Sensitive Social Protection Scheme in Indonesia**, Symposium presentation at Fourth AIDS National Meeting, Yogyakarta Indonesia, 2011
- Making Sense of Development: Experiences with Technical Assistance and Capacity development in the HIV response. Royal Tropical Institute, KIT Publishers, Amsterdam, 2010. (as one of the Authors)
- Evaluation Program Report 2009: AIDS intervention program on Injecting Drug Users, Family Health International, Jakarta, 2009 (editor)
- *Initiating Community Epidemiology Working Group in Indonesia*. Symposium session at the 16th International Conference of Drug Related Harm, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 2004.
- Handbook for Policy and Program Development for HIV Prevention among Injecting Drug Users, Directorate of Communicable Disease Control, Ministry of Health WHO Indonesia, 2003-2004. (as a Contributor and Editor)
- Advocacy Handbook for Effective HIV Prevention among Injecting Drug Users,
 Directorate of Communicable Disease Control, Ministry of Health WHO
 Indonesia, 2003-2004. (as a Contributor and Editor)
- Training Guide for Outreach on Injecting Drug User, Directorate of Communicable Disease Control, Ministry of Health WHO Indonesia, 2003-2004. (as Contributor and Editor)

CONFERENCES / TRAININGS / WORKSHOPS

Eighteenth International AIDS Conference: Vienna. 2011

- Abstract: *Changing strategy of intervention: Who to decide?* (accepted as poster presentation)
- **Writing Workshop on IDU Intervention Program**, Family Health International, *Yogyakarta, 2009*
- **Writing Workshop for UNAIDS TSF:** Documenting best practices and lesson learned, TSF SEAP, Kuala Lumpur, 2009
- **Advanced Vibrant Communication and Facilitation**, INSPIRIT Innovation Circle , *Jakarta*, 2008